Inventory of the Iris Chang papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Biographical file
  - Childhood photographs, undated (Box-folder 226: 2-3)
  - Appointment book, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 226: 4)
  - Mensa Society correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 226: 5)
- Academic career file
  Correspondence, course work, papers, and printed matter.
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 226: 6-9)
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 227: 1-3)
  - Chinese studies, 1975 (Box-folder 227: 4)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Cover letters, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 227: 5-6)
  - General, 1985-2001 (Box-folder 227: 7)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang, newspaper articles published in the Daily Illini
  - 1988 (Box-folder 228: 1-2)
  - 1989 (Box-folder 228: 3-5)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - American Society of Magazine Editors, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 228: 6)
  - General, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 229: 1)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Notebooks containing articles and stories, circa 1987-1988 (Box-folder 229: 2-5)
  - Articles and stories, circa 1987 (Box-folder 229: 6)
  - Literary magazines edited by Iris Chang
    - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 229: 7)
    - Printed copies, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 229: 9-12)
- Biographical file
  - Reading awards, 1975 (Box-folder 230: 1)
  - Poem, undated (Box-folder 230: 2)
  - Childhood artworks, undated (Box-folder 230: 3)
  - Valentines, undated (Box-folder 230: 4)
  - Primary school course work, undated (Box-folder 230: 5-7)
  - Childhood artworks, undated (Box-folder 231: 1)
  - Cards, undated (Box-folder 231: 2)
  - Primary school course work, undated (Box-folder 231: 3-4)
- Academic career file
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign
    - 1985 (Box-folder 231: 5-6)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 231: 7-8)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 232: 1)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 232: 2-3)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 232: 4-5)
  - University High School, Urbana, Illinois
    - 1981 (Box-folder 232: 6)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 232: 7)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 233: 1)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 233: 2)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 233: 3)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Open Wide, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 233: 4)
  - Associated Press, 1989 (Box-folder 233: 5)
- Biographical file
  - Childhood artworks, undated (Box-folder 233: 6)
  - Primary school course work, undated (Box-folder 233: 7)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Notebooks relating to research and writing projects
    - 1988 (Box-folder 234: 1)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 234: 2)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 234: 3-5)
  - Diaries and journals
    - 1983 (Box-folder 234: 6)
    - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 234: 7)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 234: 8)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 234: 9)
- Oversize materials
  - Portfolio containing newspaper articles written by Iris Chang for the Daily Illini and Chicago Tribune, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 235: 1)
  - Memorial tributes to Iris Chang, 2004 (Box-folder 236: 1-2)
  - Posters promoting lectures and author appearances by Iris Chang, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 236: 3-17)
  - Newsletter containing an article about Iris Chang, 1998 March/April (Box-folder 236: 18)
  - Art works and proofs relating to Open Wide, a literary magazine edited by Iris Chang, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 236: 19-21)
  - Proclamation honoring Iris Chang issued by the Oakland City Council, 2003 May 31 (Box-folder 236: 22)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Book tour, 1998 (Box-folder 237: 1-6)
    - Proofs, 1997 (Box-folder 238: 1)
    - Media, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 238: 2-3)
    - Activism, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 238: 4-5)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 2003 December 22 (Box-folder 238: 6)
    Typescript
  - Thread of the Silkworm (Box 239)
    - Notes for speech and correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 239: 1)
    - Interviews, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 239: 2-12)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Media, 1988 (Box-folder 239: 13-15)
    - Controversies arising from book and its subject matter (Box 240)
      - 1998 (Box-folder 240: 1-4)
      - 1999 (Box-folder 240: 5)
    - Media, 1998 (Box-folder 240: 6-7)
    - Book tour, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 241: 1-2)
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 241: 3-4)
    - Reviews and readers' comments, 2002 (Box-folder 241: 5-6)
    - Book tour, 1998 (Box-folder 242: 1-6)
    - Typescript, 1997 (Box-folder 243: 1)
    - Correspondence and research, 1995 (Box-folder 243: 2-6)
    - Typescript, 1997 (Box-folder 244: 1)
    - Proofs, 1997 (Box-folder 244: 2-4)
    - Correspondence and research, 1996 (Box-folder 244: 5-6)
    - Publicity and printed matter, 1998 (Box-folder 245: 1)
    - Yin, James, 1998 (Box-folder 245: 2-6)
    - Controversies arising from book and its subject matter, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 246: 1-4)
    - Correspondence and research, 1986-1998 (Box-folder 246: 5-6)
    - Fan mail
      - 1999 (Box-folder 247: 1-5)
      - 1999 (Box-folder 248: 1)
      - 2000 (Box-folder 248: 2-5)
  - Oral histories project (Box 249)
    - Proposal, 2003 (Box-folder 249: 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box-folder 249: 3-4)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - General, 2003 (Box-folder 249: 5)
  - Doolittle raid, 2003 (Box-folder 249: 6)
  - Canadian conference, 2003 (Box-folder 249: 7)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Book ideas, introduction and footnotes for Chinese in America, synopsis and moving image treatment for Rape of Nanking, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 250: 1)
    Digital files on one 3.5-inch, 2 MB floppy disk. Use copies available in reading room.
  - "Racism and the Rape of Nanking," speech, 2003 March 19 (Box-folder 250: 2)
- Transcript of Japanese trial, 1999 (Box-folder 250: 3-6)
  Includes correspondence.
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Press coverage
      - 1997 (Box-folder 251: 1-2)
      - 1998-1999 (Box-folder 251: 3-6)
    - Press kit, 1998 (Box-folder 251: 7)
    - Proofs, 1997 (Box-folder 252: 1-5)
    - Proofs, 1997 (Box-folder 253: 1-3)
    - Typescript, 1997 (Box-folder 253: 4-5)
    - Proofs, 1997 (Box-folder 254: 1-3)
    - Typescript, 1997 (Box-folder 254: 4-5)
    - Excerpt published in Newsweek, 1997 December 1 (Box-folder 255: 1)
    - Correspondence and publicity materials, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 255: 2-4)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies
      - 1929-1942 (Box-folder 255: 5-7)
      - 1929-1942 (Box-folder 256: 1)
      - 1946-1948 (Box-folder 256: 2)
      - 1987-1993 (Box-folder 256: 3)
  - Thread of the Silkworm
    - Correspondence and publicity materials, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 256: 4)
    - Addresses, undated (Box-folder 256: 5)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II (Boxes 257-266)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies, 1938-1996 (Box-folder 257: 1)
    - Bibliographies, undated (Box-folder 257: 2)
    - Correspondence and publicity materials, 1997 (Box-folder 257: 3-5)
    - Abridgement for audio recording, 1998 (Box-folder 258: 1)
    - Correspondence and publicity materials, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 258: 2-3)
    - Research materials, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 258: 4-5)
    - International Red Cross arm band, flag, and card, Nanking, China, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 258: 6)
    - Proofs, 1997 (Box-folder 259: 1-5)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies (Box 260)
      - 1933-1944 (Box-folder 260: 1)
      - 1994-1997 (Box-folder 260: 2-6)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies, 1954-1997 (Box-folder 261: 1-4)
    - Correspondence
      - Chiang, Kevin, 1994 (Box-folder 261: 5)
      - Shao, Tzu-ping, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 261: 6)
      - Ding, Ignatius, 1995 (Box-folder 261: 7)
    - Photocopies of photographs, 1932-1999 (Box-folder 262: 1-6)
    - Photocopies of photographs, 1932-1999 (Box-folder 263: 1-6)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies (Box 264)
      - 1984-1998 (Box-folder 264: 1-5)
      - 1932-1995 (Box-folder 265: 1-5)
      - 1938-1997 (Box-folder 266: 1-5)
  - Lectures and speeches, 1999 (Box-folder 267: 1-5)
- Role model award presented to Iris Chang, San Francisco, California, 1999 March 16 (Box-folder 267: 6)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Lectures and speeches, 1999 (Box-folder 268: 1-5)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II (Box 269)
    - Controversies arising from book and its subject matter, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 269: 1-4)
  - Speech, Mike Honda press conference, 2000 August 3 (Box-folder 269: 5)
  - Oral history project, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 269: 6)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II (Boxes 270-272)
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 2000 (Box-folder 270: 1-6)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies (Box 271)
      - 1938-1996 (Box-folder 271: 1-5)
      - 1992-1994 (Box-folder 272: 1-4)
    - Course reader, containing excerpt from book, and study guide, 1999 (Box-folder 272: 5-6)
- Writings by others
  - Kohen, Arnold S., From the Place of the Dead, New York, 1999
    - Correspondence with Iris Chang, 1999 (Box-folder 273: 1)
    - Proofs, 1999 (Box-folder 273: 2)
  - Rabe, John, The Good Man of Nanking, New York, 1998 (Box-folder 273: 3)
    Proofs
  - Lee, Orient, China's Second War with Japan, 1937-1945, circa 1984 (Box-folder 273: 4)
    Printed copy
  - Schuler, Frank and Olive, "Pearl Harbor, A Tangled Web of Lies,", 1998 (Box-folder 273: 5)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Proofs, 1997 (Box-folder 274: 1-6)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies, 1937-1995 (Box-folder 275: 1-5)
- Writings by others
  - Minatoya, Lydia, The Strangeness of Beauty, New York, 1998
    - Correspondence with Iris Chang, 1998 (Box-folder 276: 1)
    - Proofs, 1998 (Box-folder 276: 2)
  - Luo, Yan and Paul R. Collins, "Pavilion of Women,", 1999 (Box-folder 276: 3)
  - Prechtel, Martin, Long Life, Honey in the Heart, New York, 1999
    - Correspondence with Iris Chang, 1999 (Box-folder 276: 4)
    - Proofs, 1999 (Box-folder 276: 5)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies
      - 1937-1995 (Box-folder 277: 1-5)
      - 1937-1995 (Box-folder 278: 1-5)
      - 1937-1995 (Box-folder 279: 1-5)
    - Project for movie based on book (Boxes 280-281)
      - Notes by Iris Chang, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 280: 1-3)
      - Correspondence, 2003 (Box-folder 280: 4)
      - Printed matter relating to screenwriting and film production, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 280: 5-7)
      - Printed matter relating to screenwriting and film production, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 281: 1-7)
    - Book tour, 1998 (Box-folder 282: 1-6)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies, 1937-1997 (Box-folder 283: 1-5)
    - Activism, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 283: 6)
    - Activism, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 284: 1-5)
    - Book tour, 1998 (Box-folder 285: 1-5)
    - Book tour, 1998 (Box-folder 286: 1-5)
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 287: 1-3)
- Printed matter, 1998 (Box-folder 287: 4-5)
- "Big Bang!, The Musical,", 1995 (Box-folder 287: 6)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 288: 1-6)
    - Research materials, including photocopies (Boxes 289-290)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 289: 1-5)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 290: 1-3)
      - General, 1938-1995 (Box-folder 290: 4-6)
    - Book tours, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 291: 1-5)
    - Book tours, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 292: 1-3)
    - Conferences on Nanking Massacre, 1996 (Box-folder 292: 4-5)
  - Thread of the Silkworm (Box 293)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 293: 1)
    - Printed matter, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 293: 2)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 293: 3)
    - Research materials, including photocopies
      - General
        - 1982-1989 (Box-folder 293: 4-5)
        - 1937-1995 (Box-folder 294: 1-5)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 295: 1-5)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 296: 1-4)
      - General, 1937-1995 (Box-folder 296: 5-6)
      - General, 1937-1995 (Box-folder 297: 1-6)
      - General, 1937-1995 (Box-folder 298: 1-5)
      - John H. D. Rabe diaries, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 299: 1-5)
      - John H. D. Rabe diaries, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 300: 1-4)
      - John H. D. Rabe diaries, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 301: 1-5)
      - General, 1937-1997 (Box-folder 302: 1-5)
      - General, 1937-1997 (Box-folder 303: 1-5)
      - General, 1937-1997 (Box-folder 304: 1-5)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 305: 1-5)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 306: 1-5)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 307: 1-5)
      - General, 1937-1997 (Box-folder 308: 1-6)
      - General, 1937-1997 (Box-folder 309: 1-5)
    - Press release, 1997 (Box-folder 310: 1)
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 310: 2-5)
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 311: 1-5)
    - Research materials, including photocopies (Boxes 312-313)
      - General, 1967 (Box-folder 312: 1)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 312: 2-5)
      - Summaries of documents, undated (Box-folder 313: 1-4)
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 313: 5)
- Sound recordings
  - Iris Chang interview, KSFO radio, San Francisco, California, 1997 December 22 (Box-folder 314: 1)
  - Voice of America broadcasts relating to Nanking Massacre and The Rape of Nanking, 1998 November 25 - December 2 (Box-folder 314: 2)
    One compact sound cassette and related correspondence.
  - Iris Chang interview, Barbara Simpson show, KSFO radio, San Francisco, California, 1998 November 8 (Box-folder 314: 3)
  - "Peking University--Nanking Massacre,", undated (Box-folder 314: 4)
  - Iris Chang interview, WBBM radio, Chicago, Illinois, 2000 January 21 (Box-folder 314: 5)
  - Ignatius Ding speech, Commonwealth Club of California, San Francisco, California, 1999 May 4 (Box-folder 314: 6)
  - Iris Chang interview, Ted Nugent show, 1998 January 8 (Box-folder 314: 7)
    One DAT sound cassette
  - Iris Chang interview, San Ramon, California, 1998 July 13 (Box-folder 314: 8)
  - Iris Chang interview, WGN radio, Chicago, Illinois, 1998 (Box-folder 315: 1)
  - Radio Free Asia broadcast relating to The Rape of Nanking, undated (Box-folder 315: 2)
    One compact sound cassette and three photographic prints depicting Iris Chang.
  - Iris Chang interview, Ken Hamblin show, 1997 December 15 (Box-folder 315: 3)
  - Broadcast, WYSP radio, undated (Box-folder 315: 4)
- Videorecordings
  - "The Rape of Nanking,", 1999 (Box-folder 315: 5)
    One VHS videocassette and related correspondence.
  - Interview with Iris Chang, Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, Toronto, Canada, 1999 January (Box-folder 315: 6)
  - Conference on Nanking Massacre, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey, 1997 autumn; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 316: 1)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0011990.
    Professor Norman Itzkowitz speaking at the Conference on the Nanking Massacre at Princeton University.
- Sound recordings
  - Spoken word version (incomplete) of The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II, 1997 (Box-folder 316: 2-3)
  - Iris Chang interview, KPCC radio, Pasadena, California, 1998 February 3 (Box-folder 316: 4)
  - Iris Chang interview, KOST radio, Los Angeles, California, 1998 January 25 (Box-folder 316: 5)
  - "Iris Chang--Beyond Words,", 1998 January 11 (Box-folder 316: 6)
  - Iris Chang interview, Oregon Public Broadcasting, 1998 (Box-folder 316: 7)
  - Iris Chang interview, WNYC radio, undated (Box-folder 316: 8-9)
  - Iris Chang interview, G. Gordon Liddy show, WJFK radio, Washington, D.C., 1998 January 15 (Box-folder 316: 10)
  - Iris Chang interview, Jay Diamond show, WEVD radio, undated (Box-folder 316: 11)
  - Iris Chang interview, Al Malmberg show, WCCO radio, 1997 December 30 (Box-folder 316: 12)
  - Voice of America broadcast featuring Iris Chang, 1998 January 20 (Box-folder 316: 13)
  - Iris Chang interview, KUOW radio, 1998 February 3 (Box-folder 316: 14)
  - Press conference conducted by Hiraku Haga, 1999 May 20 (Box-folder 316: 15)
  - "Rainflower: A Nanjing Story,", 1998 August (Box-folder 316: 16)
  - "Tan Dun: Symphony 1997," (Box-folder 316: 17)
- Videorecordings
  - Two Interviews Regarding the Rape of Nanking, 1995 August 27 and September 3; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 317: 1)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0011992.
    Two interviews shot by Iris Chang in China, and conducted via interpreter, with unidentified Chinese subjects.
  - Panel Discussion and "Nan Jing 1937" screening, 1995 August 12; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 317: 2)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_001991.
    Home movie shot by Iris Chang in China of a panel discussion and screening of Ziniu Wu's 1995 "Nan Jing 1937," a film about the Rape of Nanking.
  - Hong Kong, Guangzhou and train to Nanking, 1995 July 18; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 317: 3)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0011996.
    Home movies shot by Iris Chang of her 1995 visit to Hong Kong, Guangzhou and trip to Nanking.
  - Tour of Nanking, circa 1995; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 317: 4)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0010673.
    Home movie of Iris Chang's trip to Nanking in summer 1995.
  - Interview with Zhu Chunyi, 1995 August 25 (Box-folder 317: 5)
  - Interview with Sun Zhaiwei, 1995 August 10; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 317: 6)
    Interview with Sun Zhaiwei by Iris Chang.
  - Interview with Wei Hu, 1997 January 17 (Box-folder 317: 7)
    One Hi-8 videocassette
  - Visits to execution sites, 1995 July 25; Two Hi-8 videocassettes (Box-folder 317: 8-9)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0008093.
  - Interview with Xia Shuqing, 1995 July 27 (Box-folder 317: 10)
  - Zhu and soldier association, undated (Box-folder 317: 11)
  - Drum tower and Zhu Chunyi, 1995 August 25 (Box-folder 318: 1)
  - Interview with Tang Shunshan, 1995 July 26 (Box-folder 318: 2)
  - Nanking Massacre museum, circa 1995; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 318: 3)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0011978.
    Home movies of Iris Chang's trip to the Nanking Massacre Museum in Nanking, China.
  - Interview with Hou Zhangqing and Liu Fonghua, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 318: 4-6)
  - Zhu and soldier association, undated (Box-folder 318: 7)
  - Interviews with Tang Shunshan and Li Xiuying, 1995 July 26-27; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 318: 8)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0011980.
    Home videos of interviews with Tang Shunshan and Li Xiuying.
  - Interview with Lu Yongxing by Iris Chang, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 318: 9)
  - Interviews with Pang Kaiming and Chen Degui, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 318: 10)
  - Interview with Hou Zhangqing, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 319: 1)
  - Interviews with Hou Zhangqing and Lu Fonghua, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 319: 2)
  - Jiuquan launch site, undated (Box-folder 319: 3)
  - Feature on John Rabe on East German TV, undated (Box-folder 319: 4-5)
  - Interview with Ron Douglas, 1994 November 26 (Box-folder 319: 6)
  - "The Nanking Triptych," part three, undated (Box-folder 319: 7)
  - Unidentified (in Chinese) recording, undated (Box-folder 319: 8)
  - Interview with Tang Shunshan, 1995 July 26 (Box-folder 320: 1)
  - Interviews with Li Xiuying and Tang Shunshan, 1995 July 26-27; One Hi-8 videocassette and one DVD (Box-folder 320: 2-3)
  - Interview with Hou Zhangqing, circa 1995 (Box-folder 320: 4-7)
    One Hi-8 videocassette and three DVDs
  - Drum tower and Zhu Chunyi, 1995 August 25 (Box-folder 320: 8-9)
    One Hi-8 videocassette and one DVD
  - Interview with Lu Yongxing by Iris Chang, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 320: 10)
  - Interview with Zhu Chunyi, 1995 August 25 (Box-folder 320: 11)
    One DVD
  - Interview with Tang Shunshan by Iris Chang, 1995 July 26 (Box-folder 320: 12)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2004c22_v_0011983.
  - Tour of Nanking and Sun Zhaiwei, 1995 August 10-13; One DVD (Box-folder 320: 13)
    Home movie of Iris Chang's trip to Nanking in August 1995, and the interview she did with Sun Zhaiwei.
  - Nanking Massacre Museum and Lu Yongxing, 1995 July 29-August 9; One DVD (Box-folder 320: 14)
    Home movies of Iris Chang's trip to the Nanking Massacre Museum in Nanking, China, and her interview with Lu Yongxing.
  - Interviews with Pang Keiming and Cheng Degui, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 320: 15)
  - Interviews with Hou Zhangqing and Lu Fonghua, 1995 July 26-29 (Box-folder 320: 16)
  - Iris Chang interview, Bookfest 1998, Palm Beach, Florida (Box-folder 321: 1)
  - "Iris Chang--Conversations," Irving Community Television Network, Irving, Texas, 1998 May 14 (Box-folder 321: 2)
  - Interview with Iris Chang, NewsNight Minnesota show, 1998 October 28 (Box-folder 321: 3)
  - Interview with Tang Shunshan by Iris Chang, 1995 July 26 (Box-folder 321: 4-5)
    Two Hi-8 videocassettes
  - Interview with Zhu Chunyi, 1995 August 25 (Box-folder 321: 6)
  - Interviews with Pang Keiming and Cheng Degui, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 321: 7)
  - Nanking Massacre Museum, 1995 August 9; One Hi-8 videocassette (Box-folder 321: 8)
  - Rape of Nanking survivor, circa 1995 (Box-folder 321: 9)
  - "Movie: The Rape of Nanking,", 1995 August 12 (Box-folder 321: 10)
  - Tour of Nanking, 1995 August 13; One Hi-8 videocassette (Box-folder 321: 11)
  - Interview with Hou Zhangqing, circa 1995 (Box-folder 321: 12)
  - Interview with Sun Zhaiwei by Iris Chang, 1995 August 10 (Box-folder 321: 13)
  - Soldier association and Jeffrey Shang, 1995 September 3 (Box-folder 321: 14)
  - Conference on Nanking Massacre, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey, 1997 Autumn; One VHS videocassette (Box-folder 322: 1)
  - Speech by Iris Chang, City Club of Cleveland, Cleveland, Ohio, 1998 October 9 (Box-folder 322: 2)
  - "50 Years of Silence" and "Tokyo Encounter,", 1994-1995 (Box-folder 322: 3)
  - "The River Flows Eastward," motion picture (in Chinese), undated (Box-folder 322: 4)
- Sound recordings
  - Iris Chang with Orville Schell, 1998 December 1 (Box-folder 322: 5)
  - Iris Chang interview, Hawaii Public Radio, undated (Box-folder 322: 6)
  - Iris Chang interview, WAMU radio, Washington, D.C., 1998 May 4 (Box-folder 322: 7)
  - Iris Chang interview, KPHN radio, Kansas City, Missouri, 1998 November 6 (Box-folder 322: 8)
  - Iris Chang interview, WBEZ radio, Chicago, Illinois, 1997 December 16 (Box-folder 322: 9)
  - Iris Chang interview, WCCO radio, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1998 October 28 (Box-folder 322: 10)
  - Iris Chang interview, Newsweek on Air, New York, New York, 1997 November 23 (Box-folder 322: 11)
  - Iris Chang interview, Ken Hamblin show, 1998 May 13 (Box-folder 322: 12)
  - Iris Chang interview, Radio Times, WHYY radio, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1998 November 19 (Box-folder 323: 1)
  - Iris Chang interview, WCBM radio, Owings Mills, Maryland, 1998 November (Box-folder 323: 2-3)